# Steve Mazanec

StevenEdwardMazanec@gmail.com | 440-478-5269 | Solon, OH

LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/stevenmazanec/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/stevenmazanec/</a> |

Github: <a href="https://github.com/stevemazanec">https://github.com/stevemazanec</a> |

Website: <a href="https://stevemazanec.github.io/Bootstrap-Portfolio/">https://stevemazanec.github.io/Bootstrap-Portfolio/</a>

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Web Developer that's calm under pressure, whether teaching overseas or managing a major client account. A firm believer in approaching problems proactively rather than reactively. Experienced working as part of a team and appreciative of the value many perspectives provide when solving a problem.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

JavaScript, Node.js, jQuery, GIT, Github, MySQL, Firebase, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Media Queries, APIs, JSON, AJAX, and the command line.

### **PROJECTS**

Politician Tweet Analyzer | Javascript, jQuery, APIs | Github | Live Backend Developer

Single-page web application for learning more about what politicians are saying, without the subjectivity of political bias

- Displays five most recent tweets from a user-selected politician using Twitter widget
- Utilizes Bootstrap, CSS, and API queries to create a recent news section, with clickable headlines from the New York Times and the Guardian
- Integrates text analysis API to objectively chart a tweet's emotion, political bias, and key words used

**L.O.D.I.** (Let Others Do It) Express, Handlebars, Javascript, Node, Sequelize | Github | Live Backend Developer

Full stack web application where users can search for housing contractors in their area

- Dynamically created, sortable tables for each worker specialty
- Dynamically created map displaying each workers radius of availability
- All pages built using Express Handlebars
- New contractors can be added, with form validation on the frontend and backend

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Professional Examination Service**

9/2011-present

Junior Account Manager

- Created software demonstration videos for our proprietary website that eased customer use of site
- Improved efficiency of payment processing for client, reducing post-exam payment window from eight weeks to four weeks

## Sun Yat-Sen University, Zhuhai, China

9/2010-7/2011

Instructor

- Developed a portion of the curriculum for third year University students in my course
- Emphasized cultural learning in addition to traditional language learning

### **EDUCATION**

# Case Western Reserve University, Cleveland, Ohio

4/2018-10/2018

Case Western Reserve University Boot Camp

An intensive 24-week long boot camp dedicated to designing and building web applications. Skills learned consisted of HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, and MySQL.

Columbia University, New York City, New York Master of the Arts

8/2013-5/2014

Political Science

Miami University, Oxford, Ohio Bachelor of Arts

8/2006-5/2010

Majored in English Literature and Minored in Chinese